Personal Info

Phone 07701346138 E-mail

jules.woodwark@gmail.com

Portfolio

juleswoodwark.dev

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/juleswoodwark

Location Edinburgh

Technical Skills

React JavaScript TypeScript HTML CSS

Experienced with:

- Redux & Redux Toolkit
- React Router, Express.js
- MongoDB, Firebase
- JSS, Styled Components, CSS Modules
- Material UI, Bootstrap
- NPM, Git, ESLint, Webpack
- Jest & React Testing Library
- GatsbyJS, GraphQL
- Google Marketing Platform
- Magento 1.x

Projects

juleswoodwark.dev

My portfolio website:

- GatsbyJS & GraphQL
- TypeScript
- Prismic Headless CMS
- Styled Components
- React Hook Form & Yup
- Context API
- Parallax Scroll

MaterialLogin

A simple login form illustrating:

- Material UI
- TypeScript
- Authentication with Firebase
- Context API
- Formik & Yup
- Styled Components
- Jest & React Testing Library

Interests

PC Building Rock Climbing Sustainability

Full clean UK Driving License held for 4 years

Jules Woodwark

Front-End Developer

Enthusiastic self-taught front-end developer with previous commercial experience in the eCommerce sector. A proven track record of adaptability to new technologies and tools, with an aptitude for problem solving. I take pride in my ability to produce lean, stable, tested and maintainable code. I relish team work and have a good understanding of Agile methodologies and the importance of achieving deadlines

Experience

Personal Development

Since my previous related position, I had a brief stint in the environmental sector, before I decided to return to web development. Since then, I have been studying, completing several online courses & bootcamps, creating countless mini applications. I have mostly focused on JavaScript and React, and I now feel ready to become a real asset as a junior front-end developer.

01/2019 -Present

Website Manager & Front-End Developer Ridgeway Leather

01/2016 -02/2018

- PHP MySQL jQuery HTML CSS I oversaw the transition of the company's website from CS-Cart to Magento. This involved:
- Managing a small internal team and coordinating work with several external developers using Asana.
- Creating CSV templates for product data for over 12,000 products.
- Installing, configuring and customizing Magento plugins.
- Creating and refining a Google Marketing campaign which increased the company's website revenue by 2,400% and its traffic by up to 2,900% during the festive period.
- Optimizing the website for both SEO & performance, achieving high scores in Google PageSpeed Insights.
- Refactoring a base theme to be mobile first and responsive, using modern CSS and best practices.
- Creating SEO rich and customer engaging landing pages.
- Creating custom HTML email templates for both marketing and the payment confirmation system.

Reference

Available upon request

Education

MSc Sustainability & Environmental Studies

University of Strathclyde
Merit

BSc Medicinal Chemistry
Newcastle University
2014

A Levels & GCSEs

Ilkley Grammar School

A Levels: Mathematics A, Chemistry A, Biology B

9 GCSEs: A* - B

2001 -2009